Guide to the John Gould Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Gould family papers
1822-1877
MS 247
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.5
(4 boxes, 1 folio)
Mercantile family of Fairfield, Connecticut. The papers consist entirely of shipping records for 23 ships in which the firm had an interest.
Gould, John
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Gould family estate, 1964.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Mercantile family of Fairfield, Connecticut. The papers consist entirely of shipping records for 23 ships in which the firm had an interest.
Business; Families; Shipping -- Connecticut; Connecticut; Fairfield (Conn.) -- Commerce; Ships' papers; Merchants; Gould, John; Gould family
- Inventory
  - Financial papers (listed by vessel)
    - Ship Arey, 1858-1863 (Box 1)
    - Sloop Barber, 1834 (Box 1)
    - Schooner Courier, 1844-1847 (Box 1)
    - Schooner Edward Vincent, 1836 (Box 1)
    - Schooner Greenway, 1845-1851, undated (Box 1)
    - Schooner Hornet, 1833, 1836-1840 (Box 1)
      General
      See also: Schooner Richmond, 1836 Oct 13
    - Bark Houston, 1834-1861 (Box 1)
    - Schooner Idaho, 1864 (Box 1)
    - Schooner Lynchburg, 1837-1840 (Box 1)
      See also: Schooner Richmond, 1838 Sep; Schooner Hornet, 1840 Jan 7 and Apr
    - Schooner Lynchburg, 1841-1848, 1868, undated (Box 2)
      See also: Schooner Richmond, 1842 May, Nov 15, 1843 Oct 20; Oversize Folio
    - Schooner Montauk, 1864 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Mountbank, 1866 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Myrtle, 1857-1861 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Nevada, 1866-1868 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Niagara, 1832 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Oregon, 1832 (Box 2)
    - Schooner Othello, 1833-1846 (Box 2)
    - Bark Rhodes, 1851-1854 (Box 3)
    - Schooner Richmond, 1833-1844, undated (Box 3)
      See also: Schooner Lynchburg, 1839 Aug 5; Oversize Folio
    - Schooner Select, 1833 (Box 3)
    - Schooner StingRay, 1854 (Box 3)
      See also: Bark Houston, 1954 Jun 15, Oct 20
    - Schooner Uncowah, 1854-1863 (Box 3)
    - Schooner Virginia, 1847-1850 (Box 3)
      See also: Oversize Folio
    - Schooner Whistler, 1862-1863 (Box 3)
  - Financial papers not relating to specific vessels, 1822, 1830-1856, 1868-1877, undated (Box 4)
  - Oversize Folio (Box 5)